Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and we are your English language guides here at EnglishPod.
我是Catherine，我们是EnglishPod的英语语言向导。
That's right and today we're going to be taking you to Christmas morning.
没错，今天我们要带你去感受圣诞节的早晨。
It's Christmas Day.
今天是圣诞节。
Oh, one of the best times of the year.
哦，一年中最美好的时光之一。
You wake up, you smell the good smell of delicious eggs and bacon and there's presents.
你醒来，闻到美味的鸡蛋和培根的香味，还有礼物。
Yeah, I guess that's when you're a kid though.
是啊，不过我想那是你小时候的事。
I guess when you're an adult, do you really get excited when you wake up for Christmas?
我想当你成年后，圣诞节醒来时你真的会兴奋吗？
Hell yeah.
当然会。
Sure do.
Yeah, I sure do.
是的，我当然会。
I love Christmas morning even as an adult.
即使作为成年人，我也喜欢圣诞节的早晨。
Especially I think because of the special breakfast you get like pancakes, scrambled
尤其是因为你能吃到特别的早餐，比如煎饼、炒
eggs.
鸡蛋。
But anyways, we're going to be taking a look at a situation here where a kid is opening
但不管怎样，我们要看一个场景，一个孩子正在拆
Christmas presents and we're preparing a meal for Christmas because that day people are
圣诞礼物，我们正在准备圣诞大餐，因为那天人们
going to come over.
会来。
So let's listen to this dialogue for the first time.
那么，让我们第一次听这段对话。
Dad, dad, dad, wake up.
爸爸，爸爸，爸爸，快醒醒。
It's Christmas.
圣诞节到了。
Timmy, it's too early for this.
蒂米，现在太早了。
Look, it's six in the morning.
看，才早上六点。
Go back to bed.
回去睡觉。
No way.
不行。
Santa already came and left all our presents.
圣诞老人已经来过了，把我们的礼物都留下了。
Can we go open them, please, please?
我们能去拆开它们吗，求求你了？
Of course we can, honey.
当然可以，亲爱的。
Bill, come on, get dressed.
比尔，快点，穿好衣服。
Fine.
好吧。
Not like Santa brought me any gifts.
反正圣诞老人也没给我带礼物。
Bill, honestly, you can be such a grouch sometimes.
比尔，说真的，你有时候真是个脾气暴躁的人。
Look at all these presents under the Christmas tree.
看看圣诞树下的这些礼物。
Awesome.
太棒了。
All right, Timmy, knock yourself out.
好了，蒂米，尽情玩吧。
We should get ready and head to the market to buy everything for Christmas dinner tonight.
我们应该准备好，去市场买今晚圣诞晚餐的所有东西。
Yeah, you're right.
是的，你说得对。
It's the first time we're hosting Christmas dinner at our house, so everything has to
这是我们第一次在自己家举办圣诞晚餐，所以一切都要
be perfect.
完美。
I got the list right here.
我这里有清单。
Ham, turkey, mashed potatoes, ingredients for the gravy, and of course, yams.
火腿、火鸡、土豆泥、肉汁的配料，当然还有山药。
My dad offered to bring the eggnog, so we should be set.
我爸爸说要带蛋奶酒来，所以我们应该准备好了。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So there were a couple of different and interesting words there, so let's take a look at them
所以那里有几个不同且有趣的词，现在让我们在“语言要点”中看看它们。
now in Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Language Takeaway.
Okay, this first word is not a very happy word.
好的，第一个词不是一个很开心的词。
It's a word that we try not to use too much around the Christmas season, but sometimes
这是一个我们在圣诞节期间尽量少用的词，但有时
you're just tired of people because the holidays is all about people and doing stuff.
你只是对人们感到厌烦，因为假期就是关于人和做事。
Someone who is not being very happy, someone who's a little bit grumpy is called a grouch.
一个不太开心、有点脾气暴躁的人被称为“grouch”。
Okay, so a person that's not very happy, not very friendly is a grouch.
好的，所以一个不太开心、不太友好的人就是“grouch”。
I don't want to open presents.
我不想拆礼物。
This is stupid.
这很蠢。
Okay, that's a grouch.
好的，那就是个“grouch”。
Okay, so a person is a grouch, or you can act like a grouch, or be a grouch.
好的，所以一个人可以是“grouch”，或者你可以表现得像个“grouch”，或者成为“grouch”。
Don't be a grouch!
别当个“grouch”！
All right.
好的。
And, well, they were talking about heading to the market to buy something for dinner,
而且，嗯，他们谈到要去市场买晚餐的东西，
so to head to.
所以是“head to”。
Okay, to head to is a way to say to go towards some place or to go somewhere.
好的，“head to”是一种表达去某个地方或前往某处的方式。
All right, so if I'm driving my car and you ask me where I'm going, I'm saying,
好的，所以如果我开车，你问我去哪里，我会说，
oh, I'm heading to the bank.
哦，我正要去银行。
Right, so to head to means to be on your way somewhere, I'm going somewhere.
对，所以“head to”意思是正在去某处的路上，我要去某个地方。
It's a way to say that you're in the process of going.
这是一种表达你正在去的过程中的方式。
You can't say, next year I will head to Alaska.
你不能说，明年我会去阿拉斯加。
It doesn't make as much sense.
这不太合理。
You usually say, I'm heading to the bank, or let's head to the market.
你通常会说，我正要去银行，或者我们去市场吧。
And well, they were talking about heading to the market because they are hosting Christmas
而且，嗯，他们谈到去市场是因为他们要举办圣诞
dinner, so to host.
晚餐，所以是“host”。
To host is a very important holiday term.
“Host”是一个非常重要的节日术语。
It's a verb, you do it, and it means that you are the person who has the special dinner
它是一个动词，你来做，意思是你是举办特别晚餐的人，
and your friends and family, they come to your house.
你的朋友和家人会来你家。
Okay, so we could say, this Christmas, I'm hosting the dinner at my house.
好的，所以我们可以说，这个圣诞节，我在我家举办晚餐。
So, I want everyone to come to my house and eat.
所以，我希望每个人都来我家吃饭。
All right, and it can also be a noun, right?
好的，它也可以是一个名词，对吧？
You can say, I am a host.
你可以说，我是主人。
Exactly.
没错。
I'm the host of this dinner.
我是这次晚餐的主人。
Right, and it doesn't have to be holidays either.
对，而且它也不一定只用于假期。
You could say, hey, Marco, how about you host a dinner next week?
你可以说，嘿，Marco，你下周办个晚餐怎么样？
I'll come.
我会来的。
Right, okay.
对，好的。
I'll bring wine.
我会带酒来。
All right, so to host a dinner or to host a party, etc.
好的，所以是举办晚餐或举办派对等。
And our fourth word for language takeaway is probably the most popular drink during
我们的第四个语言要点词可能是圣诞节期间最受欢迎的饮料，
the Christmas season, eggnog.
蛋奶酒。
Okay, it sounds kind of disgusting.
好的，听起来有点恶心。
Yeah, a drink with egg.
是的，一种带鸡蛋的饮料。
But it's a very popular creamy eggy drink.
但它是一种非常受欢迎的奶油状蛋味饮料。
It's very thick and it's cream colored.
它很浓稠，是奶油色的。
And normally, you add a little bit of rum.
通常，你会加一点朗姆酒。
Okay, so it's alcoholic.
好的，所以它是含酒精的。
And you drink it warm and it's kind of just a thick, warm alcoholic beverage that's very
你热着喝，它就是一种浓稠、温热的含酒精饮料，非常
very popular and my dad loves it.
非常受欢迎，我爸爸很喜欢。
During Christmas, right?
在圣诞节期间，对吧？
During Christmas.
在圣诞节期间。
You don't have it like any other day.
其他日子你不会喝它。
No, you wouldn't want to.
不，你不会想喝的。
It's too heavy.
它太浓了。
But it's very very popular like the days before Christmas and on Christmas.
但在圣诞节前和圣诞节当天，它非常非常受欢迎。
Okay, so eggnog.
好的，所以是蛋奶酒。
Very good.
很好。
So I think we should take a look at the dialogue again and we'll be back soon with Fluency
所以我认为我们应该再看一遍对话，我们很快就会回来进行流利度
Builder.
构建环节。
Dad, dad, dad.
爸爸，爸爸，爸爸。
Wake up.
快醒醒。
It's Christmas.
圣诞节到了。
Timmy, Timmy, Timmy.
蒂米，蒂米，蒂米。
Timmy, Timmy.
蒂米，蒂米。
As a child William used to be such a spendthrift
小时候，威廉在圣诞节向日葵上曾经是个大手大脚的人。
on Christmas Sunflowers.
他曾经直接蹭到圣诞老人的衬衫上，仅此而已。
He used to rub centrally into Santa's shirt, nothing more.
现在这个巨魔突然抱怨圣诞节向日葵在太阳下被烤熟了。
Now the trollis all of a sudden complaining about the Christmas Sunflowers getting cooked
我们曾经需要新年向日葵，但没有任何最爱，蒂米是
up in the sun.
个脾气暴躁的人。
We used to need New Year's sunflowers but there weren't any Favorites and Timmy was
我们曾经需要新年向日葵，但没有任何最爱，蒂米是
praying for his brother to cook up a perfect one.
祈祷他哥哥能做出完美的菜肴。
And if you lied to Santa then you must have failed.
如果你对圣诞老人撒谎，那你肯定失败了。
People go crazy to distribute gifts.
人们疯狂地分发礼物。
Yeah, well now each has a Santa and a board and you remember you're Stu for now and suddenly
是啊，现在每人都有一个圣诞老人和一块板子，你记得你现在是斯图，然后突然……
Awesome!
太棒了！
Alright, Timmy, knock yourself out.
好了，蒂米，尽情玩吧。
We should get ready and head to the market to buy everything for Christmas dinner tonight.
我们该准备一下，去市场买今晚圣诞晚餐的所有东西。
Yeah, you're right.
是啊，你说得对。
It's the first time we're hosting Christmas dinner at our house, so everything has to
这是我们第一次在自己家举办圣诞晚餐，所以一切都要
be perfect.
完美。
I've got the list right here.
我这里有清单。
Ham, turkey, mashed potatoes, ingredients for the gravy, and of course, yams.
火腿、火鸡、土豆泥、肉汁的配料，当然还有山药。
My dad offered to bring the eggnog, so we should be set.
我爸爸说要带蛋酒来，所以我们应该够了。
Alright, we're back, so now let's take a look at a couple of phrases on Fluency Builder.
好了，我们回来了，现在来看看流利度练习中的几个短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度练习。
Okay, so this first phrase is a phrase that I often heard as a child because I never wanted
好的，第一个短语是我小时候经常听到的，因为我总是不想
to go to sleep.
睡觉。
So I'd go downstairs and my parents would say, Catherine, go back to bed.
所以我下楼时，我父母会说：“凯瑟琳，回床上去。”
Go back to bed.
回床上去。
Okay, go back to bed.
好的，回床上去。
So this is just a very common colloquial spoken way of saying, go back to sleep.
这只是“回去睡觉”的一种非常常见的口语说法。
Go to sleep.
去睡觉。
Be awake.
醒着。
So you can say, go to sleep, or you can say, go to bed, or if somebody has gotten out of
所以你可以说“去睡觉”，或者“上床”，如果有人下了
bed, you say, go back to bed.
床，你就说“回床上去”。
Exactly, and so parents often use this with their kids because they want their kids to
没错，父母经常对孩子这么说，因为他们希望孩子
sleep.
睡觉。
You can also say it about someone who's up at night worrying, and you say, come on, go
你也可以对晚上担心睡不着的人说：“来吧，回
back to bed.
床上去。”
Go to sleep.
去睡觉。
Relax.
放松。
Okay, and then we also saw this phrase, knock yourself out.
好的，我们还看到了这个短语：“尽情玩吧。”
Alright, Timmy, knock yourself out.
好了，蒂米，尽情玩吧。
So what is this?
这是什么意思？
Knock yourself out.
尽情玩吧。
Well, I'm not really sure where this phrase comes from.
嗯，我不太确定这个短语的来历。
I mean, to knock is like to knock on a door, right?
我的意思是，“敲”就像敲门，对吧？
But to knock yourself out, if I think about it, it probably means that you hit yourself
但“把自己敲晕”，如果我想想，可能是指你打自己的
in the head and you fall over.
头然后倒下。
But the real meaning of this is, go have fun.
但真正的意思是：去玩得开心。
Have as much fun as you can have.
尽情享受吧。
Right, have as much fun as you want.
对，想怎么玩就怎么玩。
Go knock yourself out.
去玩个痛快吧。
So the parent is saying, hey, Timmy, go have as much fun as you want.
所以家长在说，嘿，蒂米，去尽情玩吧。
Just go do it.
尽管去做吧。
Enjoy yourself.
好好享受。
Yeah, like go open all these presents.
是啊，就像去拆开所有这些礼物。
Have all the fun you want.
想怎么开心就怎么开心。
Alright, and then we saw another phrase when they finished talking about dinner and all
好的，然后我们看到了另一个短语，当他们聊完晚餐和所有
the things they have to buy.
需要买的东西时。
They said, we should be set.
他们说，我们应该准备好了。
We should be set or we are set.
我们应该准备好了，或者说我们准备好了。
Well, this is funny because she says, well, my dad's going to bring the eggnog, so we
嗯，这很有趣，因为她说，我爸爸会带蛋酒来，所以我们
should be set, which means we should have everything we need.
应该准备好了，意思是我们应该有所需的一切了。
So we don't need anything else.
所以我们不需要别的了。
We're ready.
我们准备好了。
Everything is good.
一切都没问题。
Exactly.
没错。
So we can say, we are set.
所以我们可以说，我们准备好了。
I'm set.
我准备好了。
It's a way to say, are you ready?
这是一种问法：你准备好了吗？
Are you prepared?
你准备好了吗？
Do you have everything you need?
你所有东西都带齐了吗？
So I often use this when I'm going on a trip.
所以我经常在旅行时用这个。
Are you set?
你准备好了吗？
Did you pack everything?
你行李都打包好了吗？
Are you all set?
你都准备好了吗？
Yeah.
嗯。
Alright.
好的。
I finished packing.
我打包完了。
I'm all set.
我全准备好了。
I'm ready to go.
我准备好出发了。
All set and ready to go.
全准备好，随时可以出发。
Alright.
好的。
Okay, so some interesting phrases there as well.
好的，这里也有一些有趣的短语。
Let's look at our dialogue for the last time.
让我们最后看一遍对话。
Dad, dad, dad, wake up.
爸爸，爸爸，爸爸，快醒醒。
It's Christmas.
今天是圣诞节。
Timmy, it's too early for this.
蒂米，现在太早了。
Look, it's six in the morning.
看，现在才早上六点。
Go back to bed.
回去睡觉吧。
No way.
不可能。
Santa already came and left all our presents.
圣诞老人已经来过了，把我们的礼物都留下了。
Can we go open them, please?
我们能去打开它们吗？
Please?
求你了？
Of course we can, honey.
当然可以，亲爱的。
Bill, come on, get dressed.
比尔，快点，穿好衣服。
Fine.
好的。
Not like Santa brought me any gifts.
又不是圣诞老人给我带了礼物。
Bill, honestly, you can be such a grouch sometimes.
比尔，说真的，你有时候真是个爱抱怨的家伙。
Look at all these presents under the Christmas tree.
看看圣诞树下的这些礼物。
Awesome.
太棒了。
Alright, Timmy, knock yourself out.
好的，蒂米，尽情玩吧。
We should get ready and head to the market to buy everything for Christmas dinner tonight.
我们该准备一下，去市场买今晚圣诞大餐要用的所有东西了。
Yeah, you're right.
是的，你说得对。
It's the first time we're hosting Christmas dinner at our house, so everything has to
这是我们第一次在自己家举办圣诞晚宴，所以一切都必须
be perfect.
完美。
I've got the list right here.
我这儿就有名单。
Ham, turkey, mashed potatoes, ingredients for the gravy, and of course, yams.
火腿、火鸡、土豆泥、肉汁的配料，当然还有山药。
My dad offered to bring the eggnog, so we should be set.
我爸爸说他会带蛋奶酒来，所以我们应该没问题了。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
As you mentioned, Christmas morning is great.
正如你所说，圣诞节的早晨真是太棒了。
You open presents and breakfast.
你拆礼物，然后吃早餐。
It's a time to be together with your parents, your family, but as in this case, you can
这是一个与父母、家人团聚的时刻，但就像这个例子中，你可以
be a little bit of a grouch because you're just kind of tired because you had Thanksgiving
你有点脾气不好，因为你只是有点累，因为刚过完感恩节。
and November and then Christmas, and now you're having New Year's, so you're kind of just
11月然后是圣诞节，现在又是新年，所以你基本上就是
like, ugh.
比如，呃。
The holiday season can be exhausting, and I know a lot of families have a special dinner
节假日可能会让人筋疲力尽，我知道很多家庭都会准备一顿特别的晚餐。
on the 24th.
24号。
That's Christmas Eve, and then by the time it's Christmas Day, the 25th, you're exhausted,
那是平安夜，等到圣诞节当天，也就是25号的时候，你已经累得不行了。
you didn't get any sleep, you might have had too much to drink last night, and so it can
你昨晚没睡好，可能喝太多了，所以这可能会
be very tiring.
非常累人。
Also, because the kids always get up way too early, like 6 o'clock.
而且，因为孩子们总是起得太早，比如六点钟。
Right, to open their presents, right?
对，拆他们的礼物，对吧？
And then they'll be playing with their toys all day, and you'll have a headache.
然后他们就会整天玩玩具，而你则会头疼。
But it's a great season to spend time with the family, and we want to know how you spend
但这是个和家人共度的好时节，我们想知道你是怎么过的。
your Christmas Eve and your Christmas morning, so why don't you come to our website EnglishPod.com
你的平安夜和圣诞早晨，所以不如来我们的网站 EnglishPod.com 看看吧。
and leave your questions and comments there as well.
并且你也可以在那里留下你的问题和评论。
We're looking forward to hearing from you.
我们期待您的回复。
Again, happy holiday season, and until next time.
再次祝您节日快乐，下次再见。
Bye.
再见。
энергetic guitar music
充满活力的吉他音乐